Guide to the Bacon Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- 1970 August addition, 1819-1933; Part II
  - Subject file, Series IV
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr.
      - Drawings: plans for brush for cleaning bedpans, Undated (Box 11)
      - Invitations, menus, etc., 1888-1937 (Box 11)
      - Legal affairs, Undated (Box 11)
      - Mailing list, for manuscripts, Undated (Box 11)
      - (Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr.), medical notes: comments on Sajous International Secretions, notes for essay on arterial peristolsis, notebook, Undated (Box 11)
      - Medical school, Undated (Box 11)
      - Patent, Undated (Box 11)
      - Physicians and Surgeons Hospital Records, 1913-1915 (Box 11)
      - Reunion write-up, 1933 (Box 11)
      - Surgeon (Army and Public Health Service)
        - Annual reports of service, 1920-1922 (Box 11)
        - Clinical reports on patents, Undated (Box 11)
        - Correspondence and accompanying material from alphabetical file, 1920-1921 (Box 11)
        - Correspondence course, letters, and memoranda, Undated (Box 11)
        - General correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 11)
        - Grace Hospital, correspondence and memoranda, 1921 (Box 11)
        - Hospital routine schedules, Undated (Box 11)
        - Manuscript reports on clinical techniques, printed, and mimeo, Undated (Box 11)
        - Personal status, correspondence and papers, 1920-1923 (Box 11)
        - Reports, special, 1920-1921 (Box 11)
        - Student officers, correspondence, 1919-1921 (Box 11)
        - Uniform buttons, Undated (Box 11)
        - War Department correspondence and memoranda, 1919-1923 (Box 11)
      - Yale University Class of 1888, Undated (Box 11)
    - Bacon, Theodore D.
      - Civic League of Salem, notes, minutes, records, 1905-1914 (Box 11)
      - Diary, 1889 (Box 11)
      - Notes, from church and sunday school, Undated (Box 11)
    - Bacon Family
      - Auction lists, Undated (Box 11)
      - Geneology, Undated (Box 11)
      - Semons (list), given by various family members, Undated (Box 11)
    - (Bacon Family?)
      - Blueprints, Undated (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous, note and photstat of comet patterns, Undated (Box 11)
      - Religious school book, pictures and comments, of Willard Farewell, a student, Undated (Box 11)
- 1976-1979 additions, 1825-1952; Part III
  - 1976 August addition
    - Correspondence of Leonard Bacon, 1828 December 27-1881 December 30, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-18)
    - Other Correspondence
      Most of these letters concern George B. Nutting and his case against the Prudential Committee of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. Related material may be found in the previous folders, especially in Nutting's correspondence with Leonard Bacon.
      - 1854 August 27-1868 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1869 May 10-July 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - 1871 September 28-1879 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Papers concerning Constantinople, 1842 October 10-1869 June 26, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Papers concerning Yale Divinity School
      - Printed list, "donations for the Divinity Hall, of Yale College", [post-1869 December 25] (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Pencil diagram, "Plan for Divinity School", Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper clippings by and about Leonard Bacon, 1871 June 15-1919 May 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Papers concerning sesquicentennial anniversary of Leonard Bacon's birth, 1951 November 30-1952 March (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Leonard Bacon manuscripts
      - "Essay read at Andover Seminary", essay concerning Assyrian excavations, poem "Priere pou tous" (in English), Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Mimeograph, "Light Out of Darkness: Three Sermons of Consolation and Instruction,...by Leonard Bacon." 1840, 1844, 1848, 1898 May (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Signed and annotated by Leonard Woolsey Bacon.
    - Printed order of worship, "Order of Exercises at the Installation of Reverend George L. Walker, as Pastor of the First Church in New Haven, November 18th, 1868", 1868 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Includes text of hymn, "Here, Lord of life and light, to thee" composed by Leonard Bacon (1825 Mar 9).
    - Printed sermons, speeches, and essays by Leonard Bacon
      - "A Plea for Africa,...", 1825 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - The National Preacher Issue 3. Contains two Bacon sermons, "Duties of Young Christians" and "The Example of Christ.", 1828 June (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - "The Duties Connected with the Present Commercial Distress", 1837 May 21, 23 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - "A Discourse on the Traffic in Spirituous Liquors", 1838 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - "A Discourse on the Death of William Henry Harrison,...", 1841 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - The American National Preacher XV. 6. Contains two Bacon sermons, "The Primitive Christians" and "What it is to Become a Christian", 1841 June (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - The American National Preacher XVI. 10. Contents include on Bacon sermon, "The Day Approaching", 1842 October (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - "The House of Worship", 1843 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - "Christian Unity" (Foreign Evangelical Society) (3 copies), 1845 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - "The Christian Alliance" (Christian Alliance) (3 copies), 1845 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - "Oration, Before the Phi Beta Kappa Society of Dartmouth College" (2 copies), 1845 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - The American National Preacher XX. 2. Contents include on Bacon sermon, "The Old Age of Piety" (1845 Oct 12) (2 copies), 1846 February (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - "Discourses and Addresses at the Ordination of the Rev. Theodore Dwight Woolsey, LL.D." Included Bacon's "Sermon at the Ordination" (2 copies), 1846 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - "Discourse Before the Literary Societies of Hamilton College", 1847 July 27-1848 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - "Christianity and Learning" (Society for the Promotion of Collegiate and Theological Education at the West) (2 copies), 1847 October 26-1848 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - "A Sermon, Preached in the First Church in Guilford at the Funeral of the Rev. Aaron Dutton" (2 copies), 1849 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - "A Sermon...on Completing the Twenty-Fifth Year of the Author's Service in the Pastoral Office" (2 copies), 1850 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - "A Letter from the Rev. Leonard Bacon, D.D., to the Church and Congregation under His Charge", 1851 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - "The Higher Law" (Thanksgiving Day) (2 copies), 1851 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - The American National Preacher XXVI. 1. Contents include one Bacon sermon, "God's Work in the Midst of the Years", 1852 January (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "The American Church" (American Home Missionary Society) (2 copies), 1852 May (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "The Relation of Faith to Missions" (American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions) (2 copies), 1852 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "The Morality of the Nebraska Bill" (reprint from the New Englander ), 1854 May (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "The Relation of Faith to Missions" (American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions) (2 copies), 1852 May (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "The Relation of Christianity to Law and Government" (Society of Phi Beta Kappa, Harvard University), 1856 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - "Two Sermons Preached to the First Church in New Haven, on a Day of Fasting" (2 copies), 1857 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Memorial of Nathaniel W. Taylor, D.D. (includes a sermon by Bacon) (2 copies), 1858 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - "The Growth of the Kingdom of Heaven" (Congregational Board of Publication), 1858 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "A Commemorative Discourse, on the Completion of Fifty Years from the Founding of Theological Seminary at Andover", 1858 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "Established in Righteousness" (Thanksgiving Day), 1859 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "The Jugglers Detected", 1860 December 30-1861 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "Conciliation", 1862 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "Reply to Professor Parker's Letters,..." (reprint from the New Englander ), 1863 April (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - "The Beloved Physician: A Discourse,...at the Interment of Jonathan Knight, M.D.,...", 1864 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - "A Discourse...at the Funeral of the Rev. Samuel W.S. Dutton, D.D.,..." (2 copies), 1866 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Memorial of Elisha Lord Cleaveland (includes funeral discourse by Bacon), 1866 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Four Commemorative Discourses, 1865 February 19-1866 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "An Adequate Ministry" (American Educaton Society), 1869 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Addresses at the Laying of the Corner stone of the Divinity Hall of the Theological Department of Yale College (includes address by Bacon), 1869 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "A Voice from 'Squashville'" (reprint from the New Englander ), 1870 October (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "Discourse at the Funeral of Rev. Edwin R. Gilbert", 1874 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "Half-century Sermon" (2 copies), 1875 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "The Old Way" (American Home Missionary Society) (3 copies), 1876 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - "New Haven One Hundred Years Ago", 1876 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Sermons preached in the First Church of Christ in Hartford, by Leonard Bacon, D.D., L.L.D., and Rev. George Leon Walker, D.D.,..., 1879 May 30, June 4 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Three civic orations for New Haven, 1876 July 4, 1879 May 30-July 4 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - "The Constitution of Yale College" (reprint from the New Englander ) (2 copies), 1881 July (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Printed speeches and essays about Leonard Bacon
      - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, "A Discourse Delivered in the Memorial Presbyterian Church, Detroit, Michigan, on Occasion of the Unveiling of a Tablet, in Memory of the late Leonard Bacon, D.D.", 1882 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Bradley, Franklin S., "Recollections of Dr. Leonard Bacon", [1882?] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1977 August addition
    Consists of day journals and diaries of Leonard Bacon with accounting and memorandum sections. 35 items. 1828-1881 [if the months are not listed, the diary covers the entire year; an asterisk (*) means loose items have been removed, enclosed in bond paper, and placed in folder 8].
    - Day journals and diaries
      - 1828 October 27-1830 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1838 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1841 January 1-May 2 (*) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1851-1852 (*) (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1853 January 2-1854 December 28 (*) (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1855 January 1-December 29 (*) (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1856 (*) (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1857 January-December 29 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 1857 June 17-27 (*) (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1858-1861 (*) (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1862 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1863 (*) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1864-1867 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1868 (*) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1869 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1870 January 1-December 30 (*) (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1871-1873 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1874 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1875 (*) (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1876-1877 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1878-1881 December 23 (*) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Items removed from day journals and letters, Circa 1811-circa 1881 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Included are checks, receipts, accounting lists, notes and note fragments, hymns, advertisements, calling cards with Leonard Bacon's signature, clippings, ALS, prescription, trolly ticket, list of names, outline, resolution, and a piece of Arnica Court Plaster ["cures Rheumatism, Sciatica, Pleurisy..."].
    - Notebooks, printed matter
      Items belonging to Leonard Bacon, regarding the Congregational ministry and theology, records of secular and ecclesiastical associations, letterbooks.
      An asterisk (*) indicates that items have been removed, enclosed in bond, and placed in folder 8.
      - "Common Place Book #1", 1819 October 29-1823 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "Course of Study book", pages 5-59 (*), 1823 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        [a note fragment was removed from page 57 and enclosed in bond, see folder] [Letterbook] 1829-1864, pp 67-113.
      - Small letterbook (3.5 in x 5.5 in), listing date, correspondent, mode of delivery, and subject, 1824 June 17-1825 July 7 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "Records of the Congregational Clery of Connecticut" (*), 1826 May 3-1830 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        [a resolution and an outline were removed and enclosed in on paper, see folder 8]
      - "Articles of the North Consociation of Litchfield County," pamphlet, 1826 September 27 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "The Constitution of the Associated Churches in the Southern District of the County of Litchfield, inthe State of Connecticut," pamphlet, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "Rules of the Association and Consociation of the Eastern District of Fairfield County," pamphlet, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "Common Place Book" (*), [1834 or post-1834] (Box 2, Folder 11)
        [notes were removed from a section entitled "Historical Notes and References" between pages 60-61, and enclosed in bond paper, see folder 8] [mold on interior of binding]
      - "Rules of the Consociation of Windham County, Connecticut," pamphlet, 1837 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - AL, "Hartford South [Dr. Chapin] to Reverend Leonard Bacon, chairman of the committee, &c.", 1837 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        17 x 13.25 in, [found with bundle marked "Records of Consociations, Associations, etc. Milford + (folder 10)]
      - Librarian's record of the "Young Men's Association connected with N.E. Cong[regational?] Church", 1859 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        1 page; the volume was later used for theological notes.
      - "Catechism: Lesson IX--God's Providence," pamphlet, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - "A Confession of Faith and Church Covenant, received in the First Church of Christ in Hartford," pamphlet, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Other papers
      - "Records of the Minutes of the Meetings of a number of brethren in the gospel ministry for mutual improvement in the county of New Haven began July 1906" ["question in divinity" slips for discussion at meetings were removed from 1811 Jul 30, and enclosed in bond paper, see folder 8] (*), 1811 July 1-1821 August 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - "Editorials from a Detroit paper...presumably by Theodore Davenport Bacon [1863-1930], scrapbook, 1900 October-December (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1978 July addition
    - Sermons
      - 1871-1884 May (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1884 July-1886 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1887-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - I-III, V, VI, VIII, IX, XII-XIV, XVIII, XIX, 1876-1885, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - XX-XXXIV, XXVI, XXVIII, XXX, 1858-1895 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1979 November addition
    - 2 leather bound photograph albums. With inscription: a birthday gift from Florence to Emma, Springfield, Massachusetts, 1879 January 13, undated (Box 4)
- Benjamin W. Bacon papers, [1909?]-1932; 1983 May addition
  The addition consists of material bearing upon Professor Bacon's pastorate at Oswego; classroom and lecture notes; manuscripts of articles published; and unpublished manuscripts. The unpublished manuacripts are the most significant. They number 84 and comprise of the most part, essays, articles and addresses ranging in date from 1881 to 1932. Included are the manuscripts of four books: "Papias and the Apostolic Tradition", the lectures delivered at Oxford in 1912, "The Book Q and the Synoptic Problem" (undated), "The Development of Synoptic Tradition" (1919), and "The Gospel of the Hellenists" (1929-1932).
  - Book Q and the Synoptic Problem, chapters I-X, XII-XVI, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
  - A Critical study of the Synoptic Writings for Determination of their Origin, Sources, and Credibility. (Typewritten, with manuscript corrections), Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Eight Lectures on the Life of Christ, delivered on Tuesday afternoons and evenings in the Congregational Church, Stamford, Connecticut, 1910 January 18-March 15 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Outlines of lectures delivered at Yale and elsewhere, 1913-1922 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Gospel of the Hellenists (typewritten, with manuscript corrections), this manuscript has been edited by Dr. Carl H. Kraeling, and published by Holt and Company, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
  - Three Lectures on Papias and Apostolic Tradition, delivered at the Summer School of Theology, Oxford, 1912 July 27-31 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - The Analysis of Gen. XXXII, 23 seq., Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Antecedents of the Vision at Jordan (read at N.H. Ministers' meeting), 1897 October 18 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Apostles and Disciples of Apostles in the Province of Asia, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Approaches to the Fourth Gospel (typewritten), Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Attitude of the IV Gospel toward the Baptist, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Baur's Theory of New Testament Origins from the View Point of Comparative Religion, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Bearing of the Hypothesis that Acts 1-15 is of Aramaic Origin, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Behind the Fourth Gospel, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Beneficiary Aid System (address at the Club), 1900 January 10 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Characterization of Jesus, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - The Christ as Suffering Servant in Judiasm and Christianity, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Church in Ephesus and its Gospel (five lectures at Union Theological Seminary) (typewritten), 1921 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - The Civil Sabbath, commencement essay (Professor Bacon's first publication), 1881 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chapter VIII, The Destiny of the Churches and of the Church, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Displacement of Jno. V., Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Doctrines of the Ascension and Incarnation in Paul, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Double Text Theory, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Double Text Theory of Gospels and Acts, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - An Echo of the Assumptio Mosis in Ephesians iii, 3-5, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Editorial Displacements in Luke xiv-xvii, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Epistle of the Galatians to Paul, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Ethical Preaching as a Means of Upbuilding (paper read before the Central Association of New York), 1890 December 15 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Exegesis--I. Peter III, 18 et seq. (Middlesex Ministerial meeting?), 1890 December 15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Exegesis for the Annual Meeting of the Ministers of the Middlesex Association, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Exegetical Note on Galatians VI. 7 (for the Journal of Biblical Literature), Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fact and Truth in Religion (partly typewritten), Undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fatty Degeneration of the Church, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Four Gospels (typewritten), Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - From John the Baptist to John the Theologian (typewritten), Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - God-Made and Man-Made Scripture, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "A Greek Inscription...", [1905?] (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Incarnation versus Apotheosis (club paper) (typewritten), 1925 January 7 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Influence of the Wisdom Literature on Paul, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Irenaean Tradition of Jesus' Age, Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Is Belief in Miracle Indispensible to Christianity? (address to the Men's Club, United Church, N.H.), 1899 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Jesus as 'the Suffering Servant' in Paul, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Jewish Fable in Christian Story (plan of projected book?), 1895 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [Johannine Doctrine] Chapter I-Preliminary-Relation of the Problem to the General Development of Christology, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Kata Iwannhn-Gospel of St. John, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Key to the Mind of Christ, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - A Lost Narrative of the Resurrection, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Art.III-Luke's Correction of Mark (typewritten), Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Lyric Wisdom and the Odes of Solomon, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Miracle in the Teaching and Practice of Jesus, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miracle in the Teaching and Practice of Jesus (part II), Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Modern Theories of Social Reconstruction Foreshadowed in the Gospel, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The Mystery of Christ. Exegetical study of Ephesians I.3-14, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - An Open Door in N.T. Archaeology, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Opening Address, Yale Divinity School, 1906 September 27 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Order of John 7:1, 12:50 (Persian-Samaritan period), Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Our Congregational Heritage-address at Springfield (typewritten), 1923 October 18 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pauline and Pre-Pauline Doctrines of the Atonement (article for the Hibbert Journal), Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pauline and Pre-Pauline Doctrines of the Atonement (2 articles), Undated (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - The Place of Paul in Christianity (typewritten), Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Pre-Luken Tradition of Jesus' Age, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The 'Priesthood' of James and John (typewritten), Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Quartodeciman Observance and the Lord's Day, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Quest of Q. Preliminary Studies as to the Second Source, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Recently Discovered Odes of Solomon, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Relation of Luke i-ii to the 'Second Source', Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Return to Theology (typewritten), Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Scribes who came down from Jerusalem, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Self-Witness of Acts (typewritten), Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - II. The Servant as Vessel of the Spirit, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Spirit "as a Dove", Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - A Surrender to Rationalism, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - The Teaching of Jesus as to Miracle, Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Chapter ii. The Teaching of Jesus on Miracle, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Transpositions of Text in St. John's Gospel, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - II. The Transpositions of John 8-10, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Unity and Continuity of the Church, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Was Jesus a Visionary?, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - What did Papias mean by "Oracles"?, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - What has become of the N.T.?, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chapter III. What the Kingdom of God is, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - When and Where was Peter's Denial?, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Who was Nicodemus?, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Why I am not a Unitarian, Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lecture notes, quizzes, examinations, etc., Undated (Box 9, Folder 1-12)
  - Development of the Synoptic Tradition: a study of the composition, sources, and interrelation of Matthew, Mark, Luke, and Acts (original manuscript, partly typewritten), 1919 October
    - Parts I-III, chapter 2, 1919 October (Box 10, Folder 1-12)
    - Part III chapters 3-4, pages removed from manuscript? (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence to Reverend Leonard Bacon and family members, 1841-1939; Accession 1996-M-121
  - Bingham, Hiram, 1871 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dana, James D., 1871 May 7, July 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Day, Jeremiah, 1939 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dwight, Timothy, 1884 June 10-1888 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eliot, Charles W., 1870 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Henry, Joseph, 1869 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mason, Lowell, 1860 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)